humanrightslogo.net 2011-11-12

# Logo Design Challenge For Human Rights

## Data Protection / Privacy

###  Your personal data

We care about the privacy of our users. As a user of our service you are entitled to the largest possible measure of sensitivity on our part in handling your personal data and to our commitment to a high degree of data security. What we do to satisfy the requirements of the Federal Data Protection Act (Bundesdatenschutzgesetz, BDSG) and of the Law on Data Protection in the Area of Tele Services (Gesetz über den Datenschutz bei Telediensten, TDDSG) is guided by the endeavor to reflect our respect for your privacy and your right of personality. You declare, in regard to some processing steps, that we may, in certain circumstances and to a certain extent, collect, process and use your personal data.  
Of course, you may revoke your consent at any time via email to service@jovoto.com or by mail to

Jovoto GmbH, Prinzessinnenstrasse 20, D-10969 Berlin. You may at any time request that we furnish information to you about your personal data being stored by us. Please use the above mentioned contact information.

###  USE AND COLLECTING OF DATA ACCORDING TO § 13 PARA.1 LAW ON DATA PROTECTION IN THE AREA OF TELE SERVICES

We collect your data for the sole purpose of being able to submit to you a user-friendly, efficient and secure Internet offer. We use the personal data collected and processed to inform third parties within the scope of our services, to send newsletters or for the implementation of our general terms of use (see Terms of Use) or the performance of other covenants made with you. In all other respects, our data processing is generally designed to improve our offer and enhance its security without, however, using personal data for this purpose. The above processing is performed anonymously.

###  COLLECTION AND PROCESSING OF PERSONAL DATA

According to § 14 para.1 Law on Data Protection in the Area of Tele Services  
We collect and process personal data according to § 14 para. 1 Law on Data Protection in the Area of Tele Services if you register on our website and open an account or after you have opened an account and started using our services. To create an account we will ask you to provide us with the following data (hereinafter referred to as ?inventory data?):

  * Your email address,
  * A user name of your choice, a password chosen by you. (This password will be stored in encoded form and will not be visible in plain text at any time.)

As for further personal data such as your official name, your address, a personal website or your date of birth, you may communicate them to us if you wish after the registration. You may as well upload a picture for your account. If you opt for the communication of such further particulars, they become part of your inventory data record. We may use your personal information to administer your user account or contact you. For example, we may send you marketing or promotional materials including emails or other information. Other than that the inventory data you have given voluntarily allow you to introduce yourself to other users on the Jovoto website and to communicate with them. Moreover we may use your e-mail address to send you e-mail newsletters that may contain, next to editorial content, advertising from Jovoto or from third parties. If you no longer wish to receive information by e-mail you may at any time unsubscribe from the newsletter by sending us an e-mail to service@jovoto.com.

###  Inventory data and user profile according to §15 para. 1 and 3 Law on Data Protection in the Area of Tele Services

You may, as a matter of principle, visit our webpages without disclosing your personal data. All that is stored when you visit us is the URL of the webpage through which you gained access to our offer, the name of your Internet service provider and of your Internet browser, the websites you visited within our Internet offer, date and duration of your visit, the volume of data transmitted to you during your visit and your IP address.  
The storage of these particulars is not performed by us but rather by our service provider except for your IP address, which is stored by us. For this purpose, small data files (so-called cookies) are deposited in the main memory of your computer for the time of your visit. These are so-called temporary session cookies (for permanent cookies see para. 5) which are automatically erased as soon as you close your browser window.

The session cookies provide us for internal statistical purposes with so-called session IDs for storage in tracking log data files. The data thus obtained are completely anonymous. We reserve the right to have the logs analyzed by external service providers. If we do so, we will take every precaution to ensure the security, inviolability and integrity of your data. You may at any time revoke your consent regarding the storage of your personal data (para. 2 b). Just send us an e-mail.

Our website may contain links to websites of other providers not associated with us. Once you have clicked such a link, we have no influence any more on the processing of such personal data as may as a result be transferred to third parties (such as the IP address or the URL on which the link is available). We have no influence on the conduct of third parties, so that we cannot assume any responsibility for the handling of personal data by them.

###  PASSING ON PERSONAL DATA TO THIRD PARTIES

Jovoto provides an online service where users can publish information about themselves and share those information with other users on the website. Therefore, Jovoto publishes personal data and passes them on to third parties. Except for your user name you choose what information you put on your profile. You post user information on the Site on your own risk. Your information will be visible to other users on the website.

###  If you enter a contest and win a price we will publish your user name in the course of our reporting of the contest.

We do not pass your personal data on to third parties for marketing or similar purposes. Data are passed on only if and to the extent that this is necessary for the performance of the contract of use, where we are obligated to do so by law or to the extent that this is required for the implementation of our general terms of use or the performance of other covenants made with you, or for the assertion of our rights and claims. If your personal data are to be passed on for purposes other than referred to above, we will in each case obtain your consent. If you withhold it, we will of course abstain from passing them on.

###  THIS WEBSITE USES GOOGLE ANALYTICS

  * Google Analytics uses so-called cookies, a small file containing a string of characters, to improve the quality of our service by storing user preferences and tracking user trends, such as how people search. These information (and your IP address) will be send to a Google server in the USA and stored. Google will use the information to evaluate the use of the website, to gather reports on the website activity for the webmaster and to provide more services associated with the use of the internet and the website.
  * Google may as well pass on your data to third parties if Google is obligated to do so by law or if third parties work on behalf of Google.
  * Google will by no means relate your IP address to other data stored by Google.
  * You may refuse to install cookies by resetting your browser. However, we recommend to you to leave the cookies functions switched on as only if you do will you retain the full benefit of the high level of user comfort we keep striving for. Through the use of the website you accept Google?s Terms of service stated above.

###  FURNISHING OF INFORMATION, CORRECTIONS, CANCELLATION, BLOCKAGE

You may at any time request via e-mail or mail that we furnish information to you about your personal data being stored by us. Moreover, you may at any time have the data of your user account and, consequently, your personal data corrected, blocked or cancelled by us with the only exception of those data we need for the performance of the contract of use or the enforcement of our rights and data that we are obligated to store by law.

###  COOKIES

Our websites use so-called cookies if you are registered with us and have, before logging on for a session, chosen the option of keeping your computer registered for the entire period between logging in and logging out. Cookies are small data files stored on your hard drive containing some unique information about you like your Login data, your browser type and it?s version, the URL-click stream (what websites you visited in what order on www.jovoto.com), the date and the time of your visit as well as the cookie number.

Session cookies allow you to carry information across pages of the Website and avoid having to re-enter information. Persistent cookies help us to recognize you as a unique visitor (just a number) when you return to the Website and to allow us to tailor content, advertisements and the presentation of the Website to match your preferences. To compile anonymous, aggregated statistics that allow us to understand how users use the Website and to help us improve the structure of the Website. We cannot identify you personally in this way.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies by modifying the settings in your browser. However, you may not be able to use all the interactive features of the Website if cookies are disabled.

###  SECURITY

We have taken technical and organizational measures to ensure that your personal data are protected from loss, incorrect changes or unauthorized access by third parties. For our part we consistently make sure that only authorized persons will have access to your personal data and that such access is limited to what is required for the purposes referred to above. Our security precautions are continuously being improved as better technical solutions become available.

Status: 22. Januar 2008
